A Guide to the Walter E. Lobo Papers, [date]
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Walter E. Lobo Papers, 1929-1955
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Lobo, Walter E.
Ms1985-014
2.2 Cubic Feet 3 boxes
Please note: The current finding aid includes only minimal description of the collection. If you have questions, please contact Special Collections (specref@vt.edu) for more information.
Scope and Content
Senior chemical engineer employed by M.W. Kellogg Company of New York City (with research laboratories at Jersey City, New Jersey), an architect-engineering company catering to petroleum and chemical industries. Kellogg performed contract research and development for Standard Oil Co. of New Jersey, Standard of Indiana, Texaco, Cities Service, and others. Collection consists of Lobo's microfilmed files (99 reels) dealing with natural gas and oil; thermodynamics; thermal and catalytic cracking; catalytic polymerization; hydrocracking; hydrocarbon synthesis; heat transfer; furnaces; distillation; and other petroleum and energy-related topics (including laboratory reports from Jersey City and field reports on equipment startup). A typescript catalog and index of the microfilm is available. Collection also includes a typescript translation of S.Y. Gersch's Enriched Air, originally published in Moscow in 1939; several typescript reports on German petroleum production (1945-47); and indexes to the Technical Advisory Committee of the Petroleum Industry War Council Technical Oil Mission microfilm reels (1947). Unprocessed.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Science and Technology
Contents List
- Enriched Air by S. Ya. Gersh, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Guide to Refinery Operating Costs, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Large Scale Production of Oxygen, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- The German Chemical Industry: A Bibliography of the Chemical Metallurgical and Process Industries (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Index to Microfilmed Files (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Alternate Form Available
  The paper index to the microfilm, which contains additional information about the contents of individual reels, also exists as as text-searchable PDF. The list below contains of microfilm reel titles, job numbers, reel numbers, and sheet numbers, depending on how it was labeled. The PDF includes more detatiled titles and descriptions.
- List of Process Management's Translations of I. G. Reports (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Microfilm
  Alternative Form Available
  - Glass Bath Heater Operations (Box 1)
  - Sarofim (Box 1)
  - Radiation Heat Temps [?] in Cylindrical formation [?] (Box 1)
  - Silber Thesis (Box 1)
  - Gautreaux Thesis (Box 1)
  - Radiactive Transport on a cylindrical test furnace, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Proceedings of Gas - Dottie Gould (Box 1)
  - Est. 9823/1/1-13, 1945-1948 (Box 1)
  - Est. 1029/2/13-31 (Box 1)
  - Job 5740/3/31-44, 1945-1949 (Box 1)
  - Job 6500/4/44-52, 1946-1951 (Box 1)
  - Job 6720/5/53-60, 1947-1949 (Box 1)
  - Job 8855/6/61-69, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Est. 1024/7/69-75, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
  - Est. 1024-1/8/76-97, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
  - Est. 9961/9/98-121, 1946-1948 (Box 1)
  - Job 7141/10/121-135, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Job 7141/11/135-139, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Job 7141/12/140-165, 1946-1948 (Box 1)
  - Job 7141/13/157a-189a, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Job 7141/14/159a-162a, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Est. 9485/15/163a-173, 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - Est. 9585-4/16/173-187, 1940-1941 (Box 1)
  - Est. 9564/17/187-217, 1941 (Box 1)
  - A-2-901/18/217-254, 1926-1949 (Box 1)
  - A-4-8/19/255-264, 1935-1945 (Box 1)
  - A-4-108/20/264-288, 1943-1947 (Box 1)
  - A-4-131/21/289-326, 1931-1949 (Box 1)
  - A-7-905/22/326-339, 1930-1951 (Box 1)
  - A-8-103/23/339-350, 1922-1953 (Box 1)
  - A-10-9/24/350-368, 1940-1951 (Box 1)
  - A-10-10/25/365-404, 1938-1953 (Box 1)
  - B-2-4/26/405-411, 1930-1953 (Box 1)
  - B-2-8/27/411-424, 1936-1952 (Box 1)
  - B-6-9/28/424-436, 1932-1953 (Box 1)
  - B-6-17/29/436-446, 1937-1947 (Box 1)
  - B-6-21/30/446-462, 1941-1953 (Box 1)
  - B-6-36/31/463-484, 1932-1940 (Box 1)
  - C-1-3/32/484-509, 1929-1936 (Box 1)
  - D-1-11/33/510-534, 1930-1950 (Box 1)
  - D-4-6/34/535-526, 1936-1953 (Box 1)
  - D-5-1/35/557-597, 1929-1947 (Box 1)
  - E-6-1/36/598-629, 1929-1938 (Box 1)
  - E-7-108/37/530-565, 1932-1945 (Box 1)
  - E-8-104/38/666-692, 1937-1945 (Box 1)
  - E-9-6/39/693-697, 1939-1941 (Box 1)
  - E-9-7/40/698-705, 1933-1948 (Box 1)
  - E-9-11/41/706-731, 1937-1948 (Box 1)
  - E-11-10/42/731-746, 1938-1944 (Box 1)
  - E-12-10/43/718-757, 1938-1948 (Box 1)
  - E-12-13/44/758-765, 1939-1945 (Box 1)
  - E-12-21/45/766-777, 1945-1948 (Box 1)
  - E-12-31/46/777-789, 1938-1952 (Box 1)
  - E-12-114/47/789-804, 1939-1952 (Box 1)
  - E-12-213/48/804-819, 1939-1953 (Box 1)
  - E-12-403/49/819-832, 1941-1946 (Box 1)
  - E-12-908/50/832-841, 1949-1951 (Box 1)
  - E-12-910/51/841-847, 1949-1953 (Box 1)
  - E-13-1/52/848-861, 1937-1947 (Box 1)
  - E-15-1/53/861-868, 1944-1946 (Box 1)
  - E-15-2/54/868-878, 1943-1948 (Box 1)
  - E-15-3/55/789-888, 1937-1950 (Box 1)
  - E-15-8/56/889-895, 1929-1950 (Box 1)
  - Job 900/57/896-902 (Box 1)
  - Job 900/58/903-910,+ 1948 (Box 1)
  - Job 900/59/911-917, 1945-1953 (Box 1)
  - Job 900/60/918-943, 1932-1952 (Box 1)
  - F-2-3/61/944-963, 1930-1953 (Box 1)
  - G-1-2/62/964-984, 1930-1953 (Box 1)
  - G-2-8/63/985-1010, 1939-1950 (Box 1)
  - G-5-4/64/1010-1034, 1929-1953 (Box 1)
  - G-10-1/65/1035-1055, 1929-1951 (Box 1)
  - H-2-2/66/1056-1084, 1940-1952 (Box 1)
  - K-2-4/67/1085-1105, 1937-1951 (Box 1)
  - K-5-3/68/1106-1124, 1934-1952 (Box 1)
  - L-3-3/69/1125-1142, 1929-1953 (Box 1)
  - L-5-1/70/1143-1154, 1935-1945 (Box 1)
  - L-5-10/71/1155-1170, 1928-1948 (Box 1)
  - N-2-1/72/1170-1199, 1929-1953 (Box 1)
  - T-1-1/73/1199-1213, 1937-1953 (Box 1)
  - T-2-10/74/1214-1221, 1934-1950 (Box 1)
  - U-5-2/75/1222-1239, 1940-1953 (Box 1)
  - V-1-1/76/1239-1272, 1935-1952 (Box 1)
  - W-1-12/77/1273-1287, 1929-1933 (Box 1)
  - X-1-12/78/1289-1307, 1929-1939 (Box 1)
  - X-1-32/79/1308-1323, 1926-1939 (Box 1)
  - X-1-46/80/1323-1345, 1927-1948 (Box 1)
  - X-2-18/81/1346-1353, 1930-1949 (Box 1)
  - X-3-2/82/1354-1360, 1930-1937 (Box 1)
  - X-3-10/83/1369-1371, 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - X-3-16/84A/1373-1385, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Y-1-1/84B/1386-1391 (Box 1)
  - Y-101/84C/1392 (Box 1)
  - Y-101/84/1450-1457, 1931-1945 (Box 1)
  - Y-103/85/1458-1466, 1931-1945 (Box 1)
  - Y-111/86/1466-1475, 1933-1945 (Box 1)
  - Y-402/87/1476-1485 (Box 1)
  - Y-704/88/1485-1503 (Box 1)
  - Y-903/89/1504-1517, 1945-1952 (Box 1)
  - Y-916/90/1517-1523, 1952 (Box 1)